THANIKASALAM P

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Project Manager with 20 + years of experience managing automotive projects, coordinating a team of subcontractors, and performing budget allocation and analysis. Possess a B.S. in Engineering Technology (BITS, Pilani) and Expertise in Computer Aided Engineering (CAE), NVH and Durability engineering simulations. Business trip to Japan in support of Japanese OEM Project.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SENIOR MANAGER - PRODUCT ENGINEERING

Daimler India Commercial Vehicles Ltd, Chennai, June 2015 – Present (Acquired Wright Bus India Pvt. Ltd. in Dec 2016)

- Responsible Team manager for project deliverables.
- Project coordinator for critical Steel body implementation in BSVI 10T FBV, which resulted in competitive price positioning of the product.
- Lead in establishing and tracking of Series Change management process
- Requirement gathering from market and coordination with Daimler entities providing additional features to ensure customer delight.
- Coordinated between product engineers and suppliers to ensure accuracy and timely delivery of projects.
- Coordinated cross-functionally with teams of homologation, proto build and design for timely solutions and design directions
- End to end coordination for Steel body implementation for 10T Fuso market, thereby, contributing to improvement of Contribution margin by approx. 25%

MANAGER – CAE (Computer Aided Engineering)

Stadco Automotive Pvt. Ltd., Chennai, November 2010-May 2015

- Lead an engineering team that creates simulation-based designs and methods
- Interacted with Customers for scope and requirements management.
- Supported organization in recruitment, mentoring, team building
- Lead the planning, scheduling, monitoring and reporting of all project related activities.

PROJECT MANAGER – CAE (Computer Aided Engineering)

Wipro Technologies Ltd., Bangalore, May 2000 – February 2010. (Acquired Quantech Global Service Ltd. in July 2006)

- Lead an engineering team that creates simulation-based designs and methods.
- Defined, Established Project Plan, Timeline and Tracking in Projects.
- Conducted Training Sessions on Hyper mesh and Nastran.
- Experience in FE modelling, Meshing, Connection, deck preparation,

- <u>thanikap@gmail.com</u>
- +91 87544 74545
- Chennai, Tamil Nadu
- in linkedin.com/in/ Thanikasalam-p

SKILLS

- Proficient in CAE software Hyper works, ANSA, Nastran, Ls-dyna and Abagus.
- Experienced with CAD Software Siemens NX and Engineering Client (PLM tool)
- Expert in MS Office
- Knowledge of OS- Windows & Unix
- Communication WebEx, Skype and MS meeting

EDUCATION

B.S. Engineering Technology

Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani, Rajasthan, India

B.B.A (Bachelor of Business Administration)

Annamalai University, Chidambaram, Tamil Nadu

D.M.E (Diploma in Mechanical Engineering)

P.T.Lee Chengalvaraya Naicker Polytechnic College, Chennai

CERTIFICATE COURSE

Automotive Technology

Annamalai University, Chidambaram, Tamil Nadu.

LANGUAGE

English	****
Tamil	****
Hindi	****